<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thierrydamiba.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://thierrydamiba.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-12-05T06:40:55+00:00</updated><id>https://thierrydamiba.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Thierry Damiba</title><subtitle>Thierry Damiba&apos;s Website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Learn in Public</title><link href="https://thierrydamiba.github.io/blog/2023/learn_in_public_start/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learn in Public"/><published>2023-12-04T22:19:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-04T22:19:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thierrydamiba.github.io/blog/2023/learn_in_public_start</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thierrydamiba.github.io/blog/2023/learn_in_public_start/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="understanding-the-influence-of-large-language-models-on-emerging-markets-a-journey-of-learning-in-public-on-low-resource-hardware">Understanding the Influence of Large Language Models on Emerging Markets: A Journey of Learning in Public on Low-Resource Hardware</h1> <h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>In today’s rapidly evolving digital landscape, Large Language Models (LLMs) are at the forefront of AI innovation. As a data scientist with a passion for both technology and societal progress, I’ve embarked on an exploratory journey to understand the impact of these sophisticated models, particularly in the context of emerging markets. This journey is unique because it’s undertaken on modest hardware, reflective of the technological realities in many developing regions.</p> <h2 id="the-context-emerging-markets-and-limited-resources">The Context: Emerging Markets and Limited Resources</h2> <p>Emerging markets, characterized by their vibrant economies and rapid growth, often face the dual challenge of harnessing cutting-edge technology and grappling with resource limitations. My birthplace, Burkina Faso, is a prime example. It’s a nation with immense potential yet constrained by limited access to advanced computing resources. This dichotomy forms the backdrop of my exploration.</p> <h2 id="the-learning-approach-public-and-inclusive">The Learning Approach: Public and Inclusive</h2> <p>Adopting a “learn in public” approach, I aim to demystify the complexities of LLMs and make my findings accessible to a broader audience. This method not only fosters community learning and engagement but also resonates with individuals and organizations in similar resource-constrained environments.</p> <h2 id="the-hardware-modesty-as-a-necessity">The Hardware: Modesty as a Necessity</h2> <p>My primary tool in this endeavor is a budget-friendly Acer machine, powered by an Intel Core i3 processor and 8 GB of RAM. While seemingly modest, this setup is a deliberate choice, mirroring the hardware available in many emerging markets. It challenges the notion that cutting-edge AI research is exclusive to those with access to high-end equipment.</p> <h2 id="the-exploration-llms-in-low-resource-settings">The Exploration: LLMs in Low-Resource Settings</h2> <p>My exploration revolves around practical applications of LLMs in scenarios typical of emerging markets. This includes understanding language nuances, cultural contexts, and economic implications. The goal is to uncover how LLMs can contribute to sectors like education, healthcare, and local businesses, thereby driving economic growth and social advancement.</p> <h2 id="the-impact-bridging-gaps-and-fostering-growth">The Impact: Bridging Gaps and Fostering Growth</h2> <p>By learning and experimenting in public, I hope to bridge the knowledge gap between advanced AI technologies and their application in emerging markets. This journey is not just about leveraging LLMs but also about understanding their potential to transform societies, economies, and lives in regions that stand to benefit the most.</p> <h2 id="the-pro-bono-initiative-amoeba-data">The Pro Bono Initiative: Amoeba Data</h2> <p>Complementing this personal journey is my work with Amoeba Data, a pro bono data science consultancy. Here, we assist organizations in utilizing data science and AI for social good, aligning closely with my mission to harness LLMs for societal betterment in emerging economies.</p> <h2 id="conclusion-a-call-to-collaborative-learning">Conclusion: A Call to Collaborative Learning</h2> <p>This journey is an open invitation for collaboration, learning, and innovation. It’s a testament to the power of public learning and the potential of low-resource hardware in unlocking the benefits of AI for emerging markets. Join me in this exploration, where every challenge overcome and insight gained brings us closer to a world where advanced technology is not just a privilege but a tool for universal progress.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learning about LLMs in Public]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Amoeba Data</title><link href="https://thierrydamiba.github.io/blog/2023/amoeba_data/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amoeba Data"/><published>2023-12-04T22:09:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-04T22:09:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thierrydamiba.github.io/blog/2023/amoeba_data</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thierrydamiba.github.io/blog/2023/amoeba_data/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="launching-amoeba-data-a-new-era-in-data-science-for-social-good">Launching Amoeba Data: A New Era in Data Science for Social Good</h1> <h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>Today marks a significant milestone in our journey towards leveraging data science for a greater cause. We are thrilled to announce the launch of Amoeba Data, a pro bono data science consultancy dedicated to aiding organizations that make a positive impact on the world.</p> <h2 id="the-genesis-of-amoeba-data">The Genesis of Amoeba Data</h2> <p>The idea for Amoeba Data was born from a simple yet powerful realization: the transformative power of data science is not fully harnessed in the realm of social good. With this in mind, Amoeba Data aims to bridge this gap by offering top-tier data science expertise to non-profits, NGOs, and other socially driven organizations.</p> <h3 id="our-mission">Our Mission</h3> <p>Our mission is clear – to leverage data science to help solve some of the most pressing social and environmental issues. Whether it’s through predictive analytics, machine learning models, or insightful data visualizations, we are here to make a difference.</p> <h2 id="services-offered-by-amoeba-data">Services Offered by Amoeba Data</h2> <h3 id="data-analysis-and-insight-generation">Data Analysis and Insight Generation</h3> <p>Our team is equipped to dive deep into data, extract meaningful insights, and help organizations make informed decisions.</p> <h3 id="predictive-modelling-and-machine-learning">Predictive Modelling and Machine Learning</h3> <p>We harness the power of advanced algorithms to predict trends and outcomes, enabling proactive strategies for social impact.</p> <h3 id="data-visualization-and-reporting">Data Visualization and Reporting</h3> <p>We transform complex data sets into clear, impactful visual narratives, making data accessible to all stakeholders.</p> <h2 id="collaborations-and-impact">Collaborations and Impact</h2> <p>At Amoeba Data, collaboration is at the heart of our approach. We seek to work closely with our partners, understanding their unique challenges, and tailoring our solutions to meet their needs.</p> <h3 id="past-projects-and-success-stories">Past Projects and Success Stories</h3> <p>[Insert brief descriptions of past projects, highlighting the impact and success]</p> <h2 id="join-us-on-this-journey">Join Us on This Journey</h2> <p>We invite like-minded organizations, data scientists, and volunteers to join us in this endeavor. Whether you are an organization seeking data science support or a professional willing to contribute your skills for a noble cause, there’s a place for you at Amoeba Data.</p> <h3 id="get-involved">Get Involved</h3> <p>[Details on how to get involved, contact information, and calls to action]</p> <h2 id="conclusion-a-step-towards-data-driven-change">Conclusion: A Step Towards Data-Driven Change</h2> <p>The launch of Amoeba Data is not just the beginning of a consultancy; it’s the start of a movement towards data-driven change in the social sector. We are excited about the journey ahead and the impact we can make together. Let’s turn data into action and create a better world for all. Here’s a line for us to start with.</p> <p>This line is separated from the one above by two newlines, so it will be a <em>separate paragraph</em>.</p> <p>This line is also a separate paragraph, but… This line is only separated by a single newline, so it’s a separate line in the <em>same paragraph</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Pro Bono data science consultancy]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LLMs and Emerging Markets</title><link href="https://thierrydamiba.github.io/blog/2023/emerging_markets_llm/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LLMs and Emerging Markets"/><published>2023-12-04T22:09:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-04T22:09:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thierrydamiba.github.io/blog/2023/emerging_markets_llm</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thierrydamiba.github.io/blog/2023/emerging_markets_llm/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="investigating-how-llms-help-and-hurt-emerging-markets">Investigating How LLMs Help and Hurt Emerging Markets</h1> <h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>Large Language Models (LLMs) are revolutionizing the field of artificial intelligence, offering both promising opportunities and significant challenges, especially for emerging markets. This post delves into how LLMs impact these dynamic economies, exploring both the beneficial and potentially adverse effects.</p> <h2 id="the-promise-of-llms-in-emerging-markets">The Promise of LLMs in Emerging Markets</h2> <h3 id="economic-growth-and-innovation">Economic Growth and Innovation</h3> <p>LLMs can be a driving force for innovation in emerging markets. They offer new ways to process information, automate tasks, and provide insights that can be pivotal for businesses and governments.</p> <ul> <li><strong>Improved Business Operations</strong>: LLMs can streamline various business processes, enhance customer service, and drive product innovation.</li> <li><strong>Education and Skill Development</strong>: They provide advanced educational tools, making learning more accessible and tailored.</li> </ul> <h3 id="societal-benefits">Societal Benefits</h3> <p>LLMs can significantly impact healthcare, agriculture, and other crucial sectors by providing advanced solutions and insights.</p> <ul> <li><strong>Healthcare Advancements</strong>: From diagnosis to treatment planning, LLMs can revolutionize healthcare systems in emerging economies.</li> <li><strong>Agricultural Optimization</strong>: They can offer predictions and analyses to improve crop yields and farming techniques.</li> </ul> <h2 id="the-challenges-of-llms-in-emerging-markets">The Challenges of LLMs in Emerging Markets</h2> <h3 id="digital-divide-and-accessibility">Digital Divide and Accessibility</h3> <p>One of the main challenges is the widening digital divide. The high cost of technology and lack of infrastructure can limit the accessibility of LLMs.</p> <ul> <li><strong>Inequality in Access</strong>: Not all regions or populations in emerging markets have equal access to the necessary technology.</li> <li><strong>Dependency on Foreign Technology</strong>: There’s a risk of over-reliance on technology developed in more advanced economies.</li> </ul> <h3 id="economic-and-social-impact">Economic and Social Impact</h3> <p>LLMs might also lead to job displacement and social upheaval.</p> <ul> <li><strong>Job Displacement</strong>: Automation could replace jobs faster than new ones are created.</li> <li><strong>Cultural and Ethical Concerns</strong>: LLMs, primarily developed in the West, may not adequately represent or respect the cultural diversity and ethical norms of emerging markets.</li> </ul> <h2 id="conclusion-a-balanced-approach">Conclusion: A Balanced Approach</h2> <p>The impact of LLMs on emerging markets is a double-edged sword. While they offer immense potential for growth and development, they also pose significant challenges. A balanced approach, considering both the opportunities and risks, is crucial for leveraging LLMs for the sustainable and inclusive growth of emerging markets. Collaboration, thoughtful policy-making, and investment in local technology development will be key to harnessing the full potential of LLMs in these vibrant and diverse economies.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Investigating how LLMs help and hurt emerging markets]]></summary></entry></feed>